# Charlie Billadeau

# Frontend Developer

github.com/crbilladeau in LinkedIn

Self-taught web & mobile frontend developer specializing in HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and React with over 3 years of development experience. Experienced with software testing, creating production-level apps, and software development cycles in team-based environments. Please view my portfolio for live demos of my work: crbilladeau.github.io/portfolio/

### **SKILLS**

Frontend HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React, React Native, Redux, Gatsby Backend Node.js, GraphQL, MongoDB Tools Git, JIRA, VSC, Webpack, npm, Figma, WordPress, Adobe Creative Suite Other
Agile, SCRUM, QA, Editing,
Technical Writing,
Research

#### **PROJECTS**

Watcher 🗹

July 2020 - November 2020

React, Redux, React Router, JavaScript, Firebase

- Created a responsive React web application mock-up for a movie streaming service, organized with the styled components library
- Utilized the axios library for data fetch calls to The Movie Database API
- Managed global state throughout the application using Redux reducers, React Context and React Hooks
- Implemented fully searchable and navigable pages with React Router

### New Horizons Companion 🖸

March 2020 - May 2020

React Native, JavaScript, Expo, styled components

- Developed an iOS mobile app made for the Animal Crossing: New Horizons video game, published to the iOS app store in May 2020 with 7000+ downloads to date
- Over 25,000 lines written in React Native and developed on the Expo SDK
- Coded custom search filters in JavaScript to manage array filtering by in-game character and item properties
- Implemented time-based mobile push notifications to notify users of in-game events

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Teacher** *The Blake School* ☑

2015 - present | Hopkins, MN

- Assists lead teachers with classroom activities, student development, and individual enrichment
- Creates a fun and positive learning environment and mentors young students ages Pre-K 5th grade
- Promoted to lead teacher in 2020 and accepted lead responsibilities during a challenging COVID-19 environment

Content Intern

2014 - 2014 | Chicago, IL

CharacTour 🗹

- Influenced the launch of an internet startup with over 350k current users
- Composed, edited, and designed character profiles featured on the site
- Performed A/B testing on website features and website design
- Advocated for development shift to the website's quiz features, resulting in a 169% increase in registered users

#### Quality Assurance Tester

2012 - 2013 | Eden Prairie, MN

Activision 🖪

- Tested over 15 game software titles at AAA video game company Activision for both functional and technical requirements in an agile SCRUM development cycle
- Utilized JIRA to write over 1000 issue reports on bugs found in software using formal, technical language
- Exceeded daily bug targets as a top tester, promoted to new projects, and guided other team members in a leadership role

## **EDUCATION**

Williams College 🗗

2011 - 2015 | Williamstown, MA

Political Science & History

Bachelor of Arts

GPA: 3.6 || Dean's List: 2013, 2014 || Senior Honor's Thesis